なかなかの歌声だが俺には知るかい
Decent enough voice,
but it didn't do anything for me.
やっぱ音楽の真髄は
The quintessence of music...
オーケストラだが
...is Orchestra!
アメン
Amen!
Huh? How come you're alive?
何生きてんだ　おめえ
That was a sweet sound you just made.
今のはいい音だ
We have always stood on the borderland.
I'm enjoying the view from here.
Eeny, meeny, miny, moe...
Eeny,meeny,miny,moe...
much the same
We have always stood on the borderland.
日听   yaya
I'm enjoying the view from here.
日听      奶昔
神
岛
&
诸
恶
魔
Pike or shield?  負けたくはない　でも傷つけたくもない
Pike or shield?
I don't want to lose,
but I don't want to hurt anyone either
时轴      小瑾
I took it so I could confirm
手に取って　確かめてた
きっと戻れないんだって
That there's definitely no going back
Whose side are you on?
翻译  TL旧民
(Don't want to know!) Memories are shackles
Don't want to know!  思い出は枷
注释   TL旧民
(Don't want to know!) A postscript love
Don't want to know!  後付けのlove
后期  aoi
(Don't want to know!) Your kindness is a disservice
Don't want to know!  優しさは仇
We have always stood on the borderland.
压制   娜夏
With your arms out wide, keep balanced
広げる両手　keep balance
Go the direction that lets you fly higher
より高く飛べる方へ
I want to protect
守りたいよ 僕らの翼のないこの背中に背負った
What our wingless backs here bore:
Reality and Dream
Reality & Dream
いた　見つけた
There! I've found them!
拾いますか
Should we pick them up?
いいえ　並走です
No, hug up to them. Use our car as a shield.
この車を盾に
元気よさそうな　新手が増えたぜ　千夏
We've got some lively
additions to the party, Chinatsu.
It's, like, time to speed up!
スピードアップなのだ
ネゲフ
A Negev?!
ネゲフLMG持ってんぜ
He has a Negev LMG!
あれが
Is that...
Is that Orchestra?
あれがオーケストラか
"Musica ex Machina phase.2"
Is that Orchestra?
Shoot the tires, R!
タイヤ撃てアール
I know!
分かってよ　喰らえ
Take this!
走り続けろ　お嬢
Keep running, Little Lady!
もう一度同じコース走れ
Repeat that same course again!
そろそろ演奏を締めくくるぜ
It's time we wrapped this show up.
Roger!
了解
ヤバイ
Crap!
ヤバイ　ヤバイ
Crap, crap!
Koko, they've got an M2!
ココさん　Ｍ2です
They have an M2 Browning
Machine Gun mounted inside!
奴らリアシートにＭ２重機関銃を固定してる
Wh-What are they thinking?!
なっ　何考えてんの
あの可愛い子を撃つのは悲しいけど
I'm sad about shooting that cutie,
but he won't be lonely since
he's going with all of his friends.
たくさんの仲間と一緒だから寂しくないよ
They're back!
来た
エンジンを狙え　エンジン
Aim for the engine! The engine!
よっ　横薙ぎにされる
Th-They're going to force you out of the way!
アンサンブルだぜ
It's the ensemble!
発射
Fire!
対ショック姿勢
--Take anti-shock positions!
--We already are!
とっくに対ショック
何
What?!
師匠　急ぐのだ
Master, like, hurry!
くそが
Dammit!
くそが  やっぱり生きていやがった
Shit! He's still alive!
That means the arms dealer is, too.
ってことは　武器商人もまだだな
ダメ
Don't!
M-Master...
しっ　師匠
一方も踏み出しちゃダメ
Don't take a single step out there!
いっ　一旦退いて出直そう
L-Let's pull back and try again later.
Something doesn't feel right!
嫌な予感がする
What?! So what if your hat got blown off?
ああ　帽子飛ばされたくらいでなんだ
You need to get over bein' so
friggin' superstitious, Chinatsu!
いい加減そのモーレツにジンクス気にする癖直せ　千夏
師匠
Master!
A sniper shot!
狙撃
ハートショット
Heart shot: Hit.
ヒット
He will collapse and
momentarily sit on his knees.
崩れ落ち　膝で一瞬を止まる
Headshot: Aim.
ヘッドショット
エイム
Fire.
ファイア
Headshot...
ヘッドショット
ヒット
Hit.
With that big of a gap between
the gunshot and impact...
着弾と発射音がこれだけ離れる
Lutz shot him.
ルツが撃った
It was a long-distance sniper shot
with a.388 Lapua Magnum.
338ラプアマグナムによる遠距離狙撃だ
It was from 900 meters away.
実に９００メートル
Now to see if Chinatsu enters his line of sight.
後は千夏って奴が射線に出るかどうかだな
No! No way!
そんな　そんな
Master, you--!
You turned my life upside down!
師匠あなた
あたしの人生めちゃめちゃにしておいて
You can't leave me like this!
こんな別れ方ってないでしょ
Lutz, we've been ordered to retreat.
ルツ　撤退命令だ
何言ってんだ　もう一人いるんだろ
Say what? There's still one left.
Yeah, there's still the insanely cautious one.
ああ　半端ない警戒心もった奴が残ってる
But even if she entered your line
of sight, you couldn't shoot her.
でもな
射線に出たところでお前には撃てねえよ
I'll never forgive you!
お前ら許さない
I'll kill you all!
皆殺しにしてやる
Like that's news from an assassin.
殺し屋が今さら何を
すぐに　数日中に
Right now! Within the next few days!
No, within the next few months...
いや　数か月以内に
--No, I'll take years upon years.
--Is she for real?
いや　何年も何年も
マジかよ
I'll hunt you down and tear
you apart before I kill you!
追い回してズタボロにしてから殺してやる
She's entered his line of sight!
射線に出た
A chick?!
女
子供じゃないか
She's just a kid.
We cannot shoot Target 2.
標的２　撃てません
We'll destroy the target's weapons.
標的の武器を破壊します　ルツ
Lutz!
Damn, she's fast!
はええ　くそ
Tch!
ちっ
師匠　バイバイ
Master, bye-bye.
Why... wasn't she wearing any panties?
あいつ
どうして　パンツはいてないんだ
Hey! Don't put up any meaningless resistance.
よ　無駄な抵抗すんなよ
Koko Hekmatyar, we've caught
you in the act this time.
ココ·ヘクマティアル
現行犯逮捕させてもらいますよ
What did I do?
何の現行犯
Various heinous crimes.
極悪犯罪色々
I saw the whole gunfight.
銃撃戦はじめっから見てたっつーの
There is a police officer with you,
but you don't look like a cop.
警察を連れているが　警察に見えない
Who are you?
何者
What a nitpick!
つべこべうるせーな
I'm a normal citizen.
一般市民だよ
Didn't you know citizens can
arrest someone caught in a crime?
現行犯逮捕はできんだってゆー
しらねーのか
What now, Koko?
どうする　ココ
There's nothing you can do, brat!
どうするじゃ　ねえ　ガキが
What could you possibly do? Go take a swim!
お前に何ができるんだ　泳いでろ
Have your guards retreat and come--
私兵を退いて大人しく署に来い
ほう　何それ
What's that?
A sign for a strategic retreat?
戦略的撤退の合図
Talk about cool!
かっこいいね
I can't believe you threw me
into an interrogation room.
いきなり取調室にぶち込みやがって
Could you be any ruder?
失礼にもほどがあるってゆー
I helped you out!
協力者じゃんか　俺
You pushed away a precinct
officer at the time of the arrest.
え　あなた
逮捕時に所轄の警官を押しのけておりまして
That is unacceptable behavior here,
うちではそれはまずい行為と申しますか
although I believe that
holds true for officers worldwide.
世界中どこの警察でもまずいと思いますが
But we will let you off this time.
でもまあ　今回　不問にします
Could you provide proof that
you are an intelligence officer?
あなた　諜報関係の方ということなので
証明できます
Ah, you're from America.
ああ　アメリカさんの
何そのリアク　マジうける
What's with that reaction? It's hilarious.
Could you give me your name?
名乗っていただけます
I'm Jerry Schatzberg! Not!
ジェリー·シャッツバーグ
嘘です
Call me Scarecrow.
スケアクロウって呼んでよ
That's what I'm called nowadays.
Use it in the paperwork, 'kay?
そう呼ばれてるし
書類もそれでいい
Actually, screw the official paperwork.
つーかさ　事務書類はいいから
Lemme see the criminal and your data on her.
さっさと犯罪者とデータを貸してよ
Hand over Koko Hekmatyar
and all of your data on the gunfight
ココ?ヘクマティアルの身柄と銃撃戦映した防犯カメラのデータ
recorded by your security cameras.
全部　俺に寄越せ
Gunfight? I don't know
what you're talking about.
銃撃戦
何のことだか分からないよ
'Scuse me?!
はい
Thank you for the change
of clothes and the shower.
ありがとうございます  服とシャワー
I nearly caught a cold!
風邪引くところでした
I have a headache.
私は頭痛が
How horrible!
それは大変です
Do you have a cold? Get well soon!
風邪ですか　お大事に
No, that's not it, Miss Hekmatyar.
違う違う　ミスヘクマティアル
You made such a scene that it
attracted some unwanted attention.
暴れすぎ
それはもう厄介なギャラリーを呼び寄せるほどに
Recognize the CIA agent
who goes by "Scarecrow"?
スケアクロウと呼ばれるCIA職員を
あ　さっきの
Oh, that guy?
CIA agents always need money
since they work in non-combat zones.
非戦闘地域の彼らは金欠です
I bet he's looking for a financial backer.
金づる探しでしょう
Is he persistent?
しつこいですか
Yeah. Used to this crap?
まあね　慣れっこかな
I am.
慣れっこです
It will be hard to cover this one up.
今回のモミ消しはきつい
And time consuming.
時間もかかる
警官が死んでる
Officers were killed.
Some of our protectors of the peace
貴女の私兵はホテルに拘束した
are holding your bodyguards
in custody at the hotel.
うちの公安の人間でね
It's to penalize you and save face for me.
I hope you understand.
貴女へのペナルティーと私の面子だよ
分かってね
That hurts.
それは痛い
Give my regards to your father.
お父上によろしく
You've got enough gunfight footage
for at least one Hollywood movie!
ハリウッド映画一本分くれーのドンパチをバッチリ映してるだろうが
You recorded it with all those
high-performance cameras around town!
街中にある高性能カメラでしょ
Punk! Get off my desk or I'll shoot you!
貴様　机から降りろ
撃つぞ
Don't give me this crap!
ふざけんなよ
あれか　俺を化かす気かてめえら
I know! You're trying to trick me, aren't you?
Like that'll happen!
そうはうまくいかねえぞってゆー
Hey! Who do you keep texting?
おい　さっきからチョコチョコ何のメールだ
I get it!
分かったぞ
Hold it, punk! Don't leave this room!
待て貴様
この部屋を出るな
Shut the hell up!
うるせーぞ
待って
Wait...!
ぜってー裏口
There must be a back door! Where is it?!
裏口どっちだ
Koko!
ココ
Hekmatyar!
ヘクマティアル
Oh, my. It's you.
あら　さっきの
Don't gimme that!
「あら」じゃねーよ
I'm impressed you were going
to leave through the front door!
正面玄関から出ようとは　おそれにったぜ
Nice job at making me look stupid, you scoundrel!
ナメたマネできるじゃんか
悪党が
なんだコイツ
Who is this guy?! Hold him back!
取り押さえろ
H-He's...!
コイツ
H-Hey! Hey!
I don't have time to waste on nobodies like you.
雑魚には構ってヒマがないんだ
Gotta love your arrogance!
Get fat off your money and power!
いいぜ　その高慢
金とパワーで肥え太れ
But jail time's a lot nicer than I will be!
ただ逮捕なんて甘くねえぞ　俺
Weapons dealer!
武器商人
This here Scarecrow will hunt
you down and suck you bone dry!
このケアクロウが追い回れて骨までしゃぶりつくしてやるぜ
Someone has threatened to
hunt me down twice in one day.
今日は二度も追い回す宣言をせれてしまった
I'll tear you apart before I kill you!
ズタボロにしてから殺してやらあ
...are holding your bodyguards
in custody at the hotel.
貴女の私兵はホテルに拘束した
I can't take a single step.
一歩も動けない
Jonah!
ヨナ
Koko, what happened to your face?
ココ　どうしたんだ　顔
殴られた跡だ
It looks like someone punched you.
It was that punk from earlier.
Don't worry about it.
さっきのチンピラだよ
気にしない　気にしない
ホテルのみんな警官に囲まれてなかった
Was everyone in the hotel
surrounded by police officers?
あ　これ濡れててちょうどいい
This is perfect since it's still wet.
They let me out. Might be because I'm new.
僕だけ　通れた
新入りだからじゃないか
That's kind of capricious. But whatever.
なんだか適当ね
ま　いいか
Well, let's go back.
さあ　帰ろう
Officer Jonah is outstanding!
ヨナ隊員は優秀であーる
You're kind, Jonah.
君は優しいね　ヨナ
You came to pick me up since
you were worried about me.
こうして心配して私を迎えに来てくれたり
I wouldn't kill people with guns if I was.
だったら　銃で人を殺したりしない
That's not true, Jonah.
それは違う　ヨナ
These days, even saints
carry and fire assault rifles
今どき聖人だってアサルトライフルで武装し
while preaching the love of God.
神の愛を説きながらブッ放す
It's all about your beliefs and
what makes you pull that trigger.
要は　君は何を思い何のためにトリガーを引くかだ
This may be a strange image,
君の銃弾には
but your bullets hold
a composed kindness and severity.
冷徹な厳しさと優しさが同居する
You're a soldier unlike any I've ever met.
今まで会ったことのないタイプの戦士
Isn't it baffling?
不思議だね
Where does this "kindness" come from
after all the hardships you've endured?
辛い過去を生きてきた
君のどこから「優しさ」が
Didn't you loathe weapons and arms dealers?
武器や武器商人が憎いんじゃなかったのか
Koko... I guess you're okay.
ココ
まあ いいや
おお　私だけ特別扱いかな
So I'm special? What an honor!
光栄だね
とはいっても私は他の商人となんら変わりない
Regardless, I'm no different
from the other dealers.
Your decision is still soft.
君の判断はまだヌルイ
To be kind is to be soft.
優しさはヌルさだ
That softness will make you
hesitate before pulling the trigger.
そのヌルさは引き金に一時の遅れをもたらす
This world will be unkind to one kind like you.
この世界は優しい君に優しくない
The United Nations Millennium
Development Goals have 189 countries
189か国が加盟し　掲げる
working to achieve some objectives by 2015.
2015年までに達すべき国連の「ミレニアム開発目標」
Let's look at Goals 2 and 4:
そのうちターゲット2と4
To increase the number of people
who get a full primary education
全世界の初等教育完全普及と乳幼児死亡率の削減
and to drop the death rate for children worldwide.
Supposedly it will cost 220 million dollars,
年間220億ドルが必要とされているが
but the average amount
of money allotted to weapons
その額を
近年の紛争地域で使われた武器代の年平均が越えた
in hot spots has exceeded that in recent years.
Honestly, it's unbelievable!
まったくあきれる
人は子供たちの未来よりも戦争が好きだ
People prefer war over our children's futures.
But you're a weapons dealer.
ココは武器商人なのに
So I should be happy that my wares are selling?
商品が売れて喜べがいいのに
You're right. But it's hard to say...
そうだね
でもどうだろ
Well, out of all the jobs out there,
ま　フラフラと「矛盾」したことを喋ってもいいのは
arms dealers are the only ones
who may spout out contradictions.
数多の職業の中で武器商人だけ
Is the information I tell you right or not?
私の口から出る情報は正しいか否か
Do you need it or not?
君に必要か　否か
選択しながら聞くことだ
You should determine that as you listen to me.
Next up, Jonah!
続きだ　ヨナ
Who are the majority of the people who carry guns?
最も多く銃を持っている人間は
Soldiers.
軍人だ
Sorry, but you're wrong. It's civilians.
残念ハズレ
民間人だ
Amazingly, 60% of all citizens
throughout the world carry guns.
なんと全世界の銃の60パーセントを一般市民が握っている
One out of ten has a weapon on them.
十人に一人が武装している
The army claims 37% and
the rest are owned by the police.
37パーセントが軍隊
残りが警察
Those rebel armies that the media throws
a fit over don't even possess 0.1% of the guns.
メディアが大騒ぎの反政府武装集団
彼らの銃なんか　0.1パーセントにもならない
君は昼間言った
This afternoon you said,
"Even people who have nothing to do with violence
「暴力に関係ない人も
武器を手にすると凶暴になる」と
will become vicious if they take up arms."
Is anyone out there untouched by violence?
暴力に関係ない人なんて　いったいどこにいるというのか
This is a world where you'll touch
a gun if you reach out for one.
手を伸ばせば銃に触れる世界
It's sad that we put our faith
in this, rather than in kindness.
優しさより信じられるのが
こんなものとは寂しい限りだ
Jonah, Jonah! I don't want you to die!
ヨナ　ヨナ
君は死んでほしくないな
Naturally, that goes for the others, too.
もちろん他の仲間も
Then don't jump out in front of hit men again.
だったらもう殺し屋の前に飛び出したりしないで
命がいくつあっても足りない
Cats might have nine lives, but I don't.
You were so dead on that it made me laugh!
正論すぎて笑ってしまった
ごめん　ヨナ　許して
I'm sorry, Jonah. Forgive me!
動くな
Freeze!
The second you aim that gun at me...
私に銃を向けた瞬間
...you're dead.
死ぬぞ
He's better than the guy who shot Master.
師匠を撃った奴よりスゴ腕か
I can't even tell which direction he's in.
いる方向　見当すらつかない
I lose!
負けた
You don't get it.
This was never a duel to begin with.
分かってないな
元より勝負じゃあないんだよ
It was a game of luck.
アタリかハズレかの運試しだ
Going by the weather, I figured you'd
come through the roof in three days.
天気を見るように
「三日以内」に「屋上ルート」で来る　これに賭けた
I placed my bets on that.
If you came tomorrow,
明日だったら
I would have died,
having lost concentration and morale.
気力　集中力を欠いた私がやられていた
But this is great. I wanted to talk to you.
まあ　良かった　話したいことあったし
What?
Chinatsu, why do you go around commando?
チタツ
どうしてパンツはいてないんだ
You're pissing me off!
むかつく女だ
本気で聞いてる
I'm serious! Naturally, you don't
have to give me the info for free.
もちろんただでとは言わない
If you tell me, in exchange...
教えてくれたらそのかわりに
...I shall answer your question
from when we first met.
出会い頭のお前の質問の答えてやろう
I will tell you why I sell weapons,
いつか殺されるとわかっていて
even though I know it
will someday get me killed.
それでも私が武器を売る理由
It was the day of my first
job working with Master...
あたしが師匠と組んだ初仕事の日
The target Mafioso's house was across a river.
標的マフィアの家は
川の向こうにあった
Having a wet butt felt so nasty
that I slipped my panties off.
下半身ズブ濡れなのが気持ち悪くて
こっそり下着を脱ぎ捨てた
In the ensuing fight, my aim was unusually good.
その後戦闘はやたらと弾が当たって
Master praised me since
I killed more enemies than him.
師匠より多く敵を殺したので褒められた
Your accuracy goes up
if you aren't wearing undies?
パンツを脱ぐと射撃の腕があがる
That's right!
そうだよ
What a great story!
いい話だ
Are you now?
今は
はいてるよ
I'm wearing some! Dang, you're persistent!
しつこいな
Now it's my turn.
じゃあ私の番だな
恐ろしい奴
You're a terrifying woman.
そう
Really? You're starting to pique my interest.
私は君を気に入りはじめた
I'd be willing to take you in.
Give it some thought.
飼ってやってっもいい　考えろ
Not happening. I can't forgive you...
無理だ
あたしはお前を許せない
...to the point that
I couldn't wait three whole days.
三日と待てないほどに
In Orchestra, we're artists who beat
the music of death into our targets!
我らオーケストラは
死の音楽を標的の叩き込むアーティストだ
Don't sell me short, Arms Dealer!
見損なうな武器商人
We don't work under anyone!
我々は何者の下にもつかない
I-It smells... of a summer night...
夏の夜の匂いがする
I never knew...
知らなかった
I... was always looking down at the ground...
あたし
地面ばかり見てたから
She's a... monster...
ばけ　もの
Lutz? You were here?
ルツか
来てたのか
So you saw that nasty little display...
やなトコ見られちゃったな
I'll say it since it's not easy to ask.
聞きづれぇだろがら喋ってやるよ
"Why was I able to shoot her?"
「では　どうして俺は撃てたのか」
It's simple.
簡単だ
戦友をやられた過去があるから
Because I've lost comrades before.
I lost five of them to a soldier
just like that little cutie.
五人だ
ちょうどああいうカワイコちゃんの兵隊にな
Kill, get killed, and repeat.
やって　やられて　やり返して
But when I go, you don't have to avenge me.
でも俺がやられた時にはやり返さなくていい
まったく
Sheesh! Thanks to you guys,
I had one crazy vacation.
君たちのおかげで　とんだオフだったよ
Commander?
署長　はい
Right. Yes, I know it's late.
夜分遅く
I killed off the assassin group Orchestra.
殺し屋オーケストラを仕留めました
On the roof.
屋上で　ええ　狙撃です
Right, we sniped them.
I appreciate it.
よろしくお願いします
Later--Ah! Sir, although
I couldn't provide my unit,
それでは
Trace over the thin paper
Later--Ah! Sir, although
I couldn't provide my unit,
そうだ署長
私の部隊とは別ですが
Trace over the thin paper
I can give you a bargain deal
for some sniper instructors.
狙撃のインストラクターを格安で派遣できますが
Trace over the thin paper
Right.
はい
Trace over the thin paper
Okay. A pleasure doing business with you.
はい  毎度ありがとうございます
Trace over the thin paper
To bind the scent of late summer
薄い紙をなぞって
想い馳せる記録の束
I think nostalgically upon the batch of records,
The sweet poison that twines around my arms
甘い毒が腕に絡む
I will draw closer to you once I decode them
読み解けたなら　近づけると
そんな夢を見た
That's what I saw in my dream
Flowers continue their existence
by wilting and leaving seeds behind,
花は枯れて種を残し　続いていくものだけれど
But this white flower was
only able to share one stock
この白い花はただひとつの株を分け合うしかなかった
恶魔岛字幕组(bbs.emland.net)
诸神字幕组(kamigami.org)
本字幕由   恶魔岛字幕组   &   诸神字幕组   联合制作
(bbs.emland.net)    (kamigami.org)
翻译 TL旧民        日听 yaya
注释 TL旧民        日听 奶昔
后期 aoi           压制 娜夏
仅供交流学习之用 禁止用于商业用途
诸神字幕组
恶魔岛字幕组
Her name is Koko.
She is loco.
I said, "Oh no!"
Her name is Koko.
She is loco.
I said, "Oh no!"